

# Yahor Kanapatski

### Contact

#### **Address**

New Brunswick, NJ, US

#### **Phone**

1-551-261-7868

#### **Email**

yahorwebdev@gmail.com

#### Skype

yahorwebdev@gmail.com

#### Linkedin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/yahor-kanapatski-477aa019a/

#### Skills

## Key Skills:

- · Problem-solving
- Communication
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Time Management

#### Technical Skills:

- Languages:
  - JavaScript
  - HTML
- CSS
- Python
- TypeScript

# **Professional Summary**

Likable and dedicated Senior Web Developer with over 5 years of experience in a fast-paced fin-tech company. Eager to offer superb analytical and computer skills to help HSC LLC grow its client base. In previous roles recognized for top company-wide quality satisfaction rating (over 99%). Also, reduced client wait time by 20% and boosted client satisfaction ratings by more than 40% in a single quarter.

## Work Experience

12 / 2019 - 05 / 2020

#### Upwork

Senior Full Stack Developer

- Spearheaded an initiative to develop seamless omni-channel infrastructure, increasing online sales revenue by \$3M within three months of system launch
- Lead weekly Java workshops, fostering cross-functional programming ease and efficacy
- Liaise between front-end and back-end development teams in constructing and integrating design features which accelerate delivery time by 15% and decrease site crashes by 45%
- Implemented cross-platform browser plugins, improving overall website responsiveness and functionality

04 / 2015 - 12 / 2019

## **EPAM System**

Full Stack Engineer

Website Development & Project Management

- $\bullet$  Revamp company's website via deploying responsive design & facilities an increase in mobile users by 40%
- Led a project to develop user-friendly e-commerce websites administering web development life cycle for 2 clients
- Improved user-clicks by 50% and subsequent purchase by 30% Client Relationship Management
- Identified lags in a flight ticket booking website for a leading booking portal in the country
- Deployed multi-browser capability which resulted in revenue portal in the country
- Acquired 2 new projects worth USD 20K as a result of providing exceptional results

## Front-end Developer

- Employed mastery of front-end languages (JavaScript, CSS, HTML) in collaboration with in-house web designers to create user-oriented visuals and features, increasing site traffic by 2,000 visitors per month
- Applied version control software (Git) to track, test, and update preexisting source code
- Initiated and maintained compliance with PbD framework to enhance data security, leading to a 19% reduction in hacker attacks over a one year period
- Performed unit testing to ensure optimal browser interpretation and functionality

- Front-end:
- React.JS
- Angular.JS
- Vue.JS
- Material UI
- Webpack
- Back-end:
- Node.JS
- Django
- Flask
- ETL
- RESTful APIs
- Firebase, AWS(EC2, S3)
- NLP, ML
- Database:
- SQL
- MongoDB

# Education

2011 - 2015

# **Gomel State Technical University**

Bachelor's degree, Computer Engineering